## Contact

amunoz8@asu.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/aliria-mu %C3%B1oz-rasc%C3%B3n-ph-d-rn-ccrn-k-7b7a0b79 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Nursing Education Clinical Instruction Oncology Nursing

## Languages

Spanish (Full Professional)

## Certifications

Registered Nurse

ATCN [Advanced Trauma Care Nurse]

CCRN-K [Critical Care Registered Nurse]

### Honors-Awards

Outstanding Young Alumna

Joyce Finch Award for Outstanding Teaching

DAISY Award for Extraordinary Nursing Faculty

#### **Publications**

A Whole World of Nursing

Phoenix VA Health Care System: Arizona State University College of Nursing and Health Innovation Partnership to Transform Nursing Education and Practice (PAP-NEP).

Reducing Health Care's Carbon Footprint: The Power of Nursing

# Aliria Muñoz Rascón Ph.D, RN, CCRN-K

Assistant Director at Edson Global Health Collaboratory; Clinical Associate Professor

Phoenix, Arizona Area

## Summary

I am honored to serve as Clinical Associate Professor in the prelicensure program at the Edson College of Nursing and Health Innovation. My additional role as Assistant Director of the Edson Global Health Collaboratory focuses on increasing the international footprint of the college by providing study abroad, service learning, cultural immersion, and international opportunities for students and faculty.

Along with teaching Critical Care, Evidence Based Practice, Health and Illness Concepts, Immersion Clinical Practice, Pharmacology, the Senior Capstone course and others, I enjoy working with BSN students at all levels. I also cherish my previous practice in the Intensive Care Unit where I specialized in pulmonary hypertension and medical ICU patients. My concurrent experience in the Trauma, Surgical, and Neurological ICUs involved caring for patients undergoing Rotoprone and Oscillator therapy, CRRT, rapid transfusion, and other complex interventions.

## Experience

Arizona State University

6 years 11 months

Assistant Director: Edson Global Health Collaboratory

June 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Phoenix, Arizona Area

Lead study abroad and service learning initiatives for undergraduate and graduate students at the Edson College. Engage with international and local partners to enhance the global footprint of the college.

Clinical Associate Professor August 2013 - Present (6 years 11 months)

#### Phoenix, Arizona Area

Study Abroad Faculty Director and program developer: "From Lima to Machu Picchu: Exploring Healthcare, Culture, and Ethics in Peru"

## Course development:

Health and Illness Concepts III (Complex Care components), Professional Nurse Concepts II, Transcultural Health, Community as Partner

#### Course Instruction:

Clinical Instruction, Laboratory Instruction, Lecture, Course Coordination
Coursework includes: Pharmacology (lecture), Professional Nurse Attributes
(lecture and hybrid course), Nursing Concepts (lecture), Evidence Based
Practice/Nursing Research and Application to Practice, Complex Care Theory
(lecture), Complex Care Practice (Clinical), Senior Capstone Course (lecture/
literacy course), Clinical Immersion (clinical), Adult Health/Medical Surgical
Nursing (lecture), Experiential courses from first semester to final semester of
the BSN program.

Arizona State University College of Nursing & Health Innovation Co-Director: VA Nursing Academic Partnership May 2016 - June 2018 (2 years 2 months) Phoenix. AZ

Lead and manage faculty in the VA Nursing Academic Partnership program Lead VANAP initiatives involving Veteran outreach, quality improvement, and nursing staff education

Collaborate with CONHI and VA leadership to support, manage, and lead faculty and students working within the VANAP cohort.

Prepare for and facilitate site visits and ensure program compliance with the Federal Office of Academic Affiliations

Critical Nursing Solutions, Inc. ICU Nurse January 2014 - 2016 (2 years) Phoenix, AZ

Fulfill medical, trauma, neuro, CV, and surgical ICU nurse roles working in a broad spectrum of hospital systems throughout the greater Phoenix area.

St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center 8 years

ICU Nurse

2010 - 2015 (5 years)

ICU staff nurse for Medical, Surgical, and Trauma ICUs with cross-training to the Neuro and Cardiovascular ICU.

Oncology Nurse 2007 - 2010 (3 years)

Staff nurse and charge nurse in the Medical-Surgical-Telemetry-Oncology unit caring for a broad variety of patients as well as frequent administration of chemotherapy.

# Education

University of Arizona

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Nursing · (2015 - 2019)

Arizona State University

Master of Science (MS), Nursing Education · (2012)

Hartwick College
Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing, Spanish · (2003 - 2007)